Richard Polisuk . Jarvis Consulting

I am an experienced information technology professional with systems, network, and infrastructure architecture experience. I am currently pursuing software engineering opportunities. I have extensive professional experience with IBM Canada, CIBC, and TELUS. While at IBM Canada, I worked as a mainframe software developer, was part of the Internet services team, and eventually worked with CIBC in developing their first web based banking solution. I continued working on this project once I joined CIBC and then was the Chief Architect for the CIBC VeriSign PKI product. I was involved in running, installing, configuring, and supporting the CIBC VeriSign secure datacenter environment. At TELUS Health (which was called BCE Emergis and then Emergis), I was an infrastructure Architect working in datacenter projects helping to bring products into the production environment. As well I supported the development network including switches, routers, and Load Balancers and worked on migrating this environment to a VMWare NSX virtual networking environment. My final role at TELUS was part of the TELUS Health team that was building a new AWS environment where I helped to administer many different DevOps tools. I have a Bachelor of Commerce degree with a major in Management Information Systems from McGill University and I received an Ontario College Advanced Diploma in Computer Programming and Analysis from Seneca College. While at Seneca College I learned software development and gained experience in many different programming languages, web development, networking, database systems, Big Data, and mobile development. In the future I hope to leverage all my experience to be a software developer or a DevOps developer.

Skills

Proficient: Java, JavaScript, C#, Public Cloud (AWS, Azure, GCP), Networking (Load Balancing, Firewalls)

Competent: RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Docker, Angular, Node.js/Express.js, DevOps tools (Datadog, OpsGenie, Confluence, Bitbucket, Splunk)

Familiar: MongoDB, React, Big Data (Hadoop, Spark, Python, R), Mobile (Android/Java, IOS/Swift, Xamarin, Flutter), HP ProLiant hardware

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_RichardPolisuk

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Programmed a client/server monitoring tool using Bash scripts, Docker containers, Postgres database, and SQL queries.

Highlighted Projects

Donor's Choice [GitHub]: Seneca College final project which allowed consumers to donate their clothes to any charity of their choice. Configured the MongoDB environment and loaded the charity information. Developed the required APIs to allow pickups, donations, and authentication using node.js and Express.js.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Developed a Bash script monitoring system with a Postgres database.

Senior Design Specialist, TELUS Health (2017-2019): Administered TELUS Health Cloud Operations team health applications running in Amazon Web Services (AWS) using Zendesk, OpsGenie, Atlassian suite (Confluence, JIRA, Bitbucket), Datadog, Slack, Splunk, and Python scripting.

Senior IT Architect, Emergis (after 2008, TELUS Health) (2006-2017): Worked with solution architects to understand their application requirements and translate it into documentation used by the operations staff to build out the appropriate environments. Documentation contains the network, system, and application information needed to implement the solution. Supported the development and quality assurance networks that contain all the development/QA servers. Involved in the design and installation of the network containing multi-layer switches, load balancers, firewalls, routers, and network monitoring.

Senior Infrastructure Architect, BCE Emergis (then Emergis) (2001-2006): Involved in the architecture, implementation and support of technology infrastructures needed to support Emergis' e-commerce products, services and solutions. Design and architect the network, system, and storage infrastructure, including production, test, disaster recovery and corporate environments. This includes adding new applications to the existing infrastructure and ensuring the network and security is correctly designed for these solutions.

Chief Architect, CIBC VeriSign, CIBC (2000-2001): Responsible for establishing the standard hardware configurations, obtaining price quotes from vendors and purchasing equipment; defining the network components required for various applications (routers, firewalls, etc.); selecting and configuring web and application servers; sizing network and hardware components required for specific applications; determining the load balancing, scalability and availability requirements of an application.

Advisory Systems Developer, CIBC (1998-2000): Worked with the development team to ensure the application infrastructure was correctly sized and configured. Provided support for the operations team concerning the application and required infrastructure.

Internet Specialist, IBM Canada (1989-1998): Implemented the technical infrastructure for President's Choice Financial. Designed, set up and coordinated RS/6000 SP infrastructure. Coordinated team of CIBC, INTRIA-HP and IBM resources. Coded a component of the Client/Server SEDAR application for the Canadian Depository for Securities in C and Microsoft Visual Basic. Designed and coded internal Mainframe applications for IBM Canada in REXX and ISPF for VM.

Education

Seneca College (2019-2021), Ontario College Advanced Diploma, Computer Programming and Analysis - High Honours - President's Honour List (Fall 2019, Winter 2020, Summer 2020, Fall 2020, Winter 2021, Summer 2021) - GPA: 4.0/4.0

McGill University (1986-1989), Bachelor of Commerce, Major, Management Information System - Distinction - GPA: 3.42/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Walking
- Reading